我喜欢你的西装
I like your suit.
谢谢  买了几身上班穿的新衣服
Oh, thanks. Got a couple new outfits for work.
你未婚妻的工作
How does it feel knowing your fiancee's job
是穿成那样去和医生调情
is to go out and flirt with doctors,
美艳动人
looking like that,
而你却是坐在这里
while you sit here, you know...
黯淡无光  你有何感想
looking like this?
她没有和医生调情
She doesn't flirt with doctors.
是啊  我的工作可是相当专业
Yeah. It's all very professional.
你弯腰的时候  我可以看见你的胸部
You know when you bend over, I can see down your shirt?
很好
Okay, good.
说到新事业
Speaking of new careers,
你的暗物质研究进行得怎么样了  谢尔顿
how are things going with dark matter, Sheldon?
我得说此刻是这领域历史上
Oh, yeah, I'd have to say it's the most exiting time
最激动人心的时刻
in the history of the field.
发生了什么
What's going on?
我加入了这领域
I started doing it.
政府资助要进行
You know, the government funded
目前为止最大的研究来探测暗物质
the biggest experiment yet to detect dark matter.
是的  我读过相关报道
Oh, yeah, I've read about that--
他们把研究小队送到废弃的盐矿里
they're sending research teams down into abandoned salt mines.
谢尔顿  如果我们能申请加入这些小队
Sheldon, if we apply to be one of those teams,
就能亲身参与到大事里...
we could be on the ground floor of something big--
理论物理学与天体物理学的大事
not just for theoretical physics but for astrophysics as well.
等等  你们要去矿井里工作
Wait, hang on-- you guys are gonna work in a mine?
有何不可
Why not?
车子一开进自助洗车器  你恐慌症都发作了
You had a panic attack when we went through the car wash.
你指的这种情绪应该是震惊之情
Perhaps the emotion you're referring to was shock
震惊自己居然会去清洁东西
at you having something cleaned.
我想佩妮的意思是
I think what Penny meant is,
想到你俩下矿井的画面挺有趣的
the thought of you two in a mine is kind of funny--
就像一只猫骑着自动吸尘机
it's like a cat riding a Roomba.
如果他们害怕了  就会戴上
If they get scared, they'll have those hats
顶上有灯的帽子  因为矿井下面
with the lights on them, 'cause down there
一直都是黑黑的哟
it's night-night all the time!
他们也可以
Maybe they could ride around
坐在矿车里四处溜达
in one of those mine carts that go,
嘎吱嘎吱嘎吱
ee-oo-ee-oo-ee-oo.
对  看见鬼的时候也跑得更快
Yeah, it'll help them get away when they see a gh-gh-ghost...!
-他们在取笑我俩吗  -对
- Are they making fun of us? - Yup.
好怀念我听不出言外之意的那些日子
I miss the old days when I couldn't tell.
我最爱的电子游戏之一
So, one of my favorite video games of all time
叫做《汪达与巨像》
is called Shadow of the Colossus,
是PS2独占游戏
and it was only for PlayStation 2,
但是后来他们为PS3提供了
but then they came out with a new version
画质更好的新版本
for PS3 with better graphics.
我终于有机会玩这个游戏了
I finally got the chance to play it,
由于某些原因  PS3的版本并没有PS2的好
and for some reason, it just wasn't as good as the first one.
或者我们来聊瑜伽吧
Or something about yoga.
对不起  我在想工作的事情
I'm sorry-- I was thinking about work.
我刚在说  有个电子游戏...
Well, I was just saying that there was this video game...
我就是从那个时候开始想工作的事情
Yeah, that's when I started thinking about work.
听着  我有个好消息
Uh, listen, I've got some good news.
这是给你的
This is for you.
这是什么
What is this?
你知道公司给我配了一辆车吧
Well, you know how they gave me the company car?
我没必要要两辆车  所以我卖了另外一辆
Didn't make sense to have two, so I sold the other one.
你卖了我送你的那辆吗
The one I gave you?
对  这是还你的钱
Yeah. And there's your money back--
现在我们两清了
and now we're even.
很棒吧
How great is that?
是
Uh, yeah.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
莱纳德别这样
Oh, come on, Leonard,
我知道那辆车是你的好意
I know the car was a thoughtful gesture
我也很感激
and I really appreciate it,
但是我没必要坐拥两辆车
but it doesn't make sense to have both.
-你说得对  -那我应该怎么做
- You're right. - What should I have done?
拍一张咱俩在车里的照片
Taken a picture of us in the car
放进粉色相框里
and put it in a pink frame
周围用发泡彩笔写上"世上最好的未婚夫"吗
with puffy paint around it that says "Best Fiance Ever"?
听起来不错啊
Doesn't sound that bad.
很好  因为...我就是这么做了
Well, good, because... that's why I did!
谢谢  你真是太好了
Thank you. That-that is so sweet.
不  我其实没那么好
No, it's not that sweet--
我用你的钱买了相框
I paid for the frame with your money
还做了个按摩
and then got a massage.
其实你不必给我钱
You know what, you don't have to give me this.
你留着吧
You keep it.
-为什么  -那辆车是我送你的礼物
- Why? - The car was a gift--
是你需要的东西
it was something you needed.
我很高兴能帮得上忙
I was happy to help you out.
我真的很感激  不过我现在不需要了
And I really appreciate it, but now I don't need it,
你拿着吧
so... here you go.
这样太蠢了  虽然你不需要车
Well, this is silly-- so you don't need the car,
不过你可以用这笔钱来买别的东西
but you could use it to buy yourself something else,
比如  买个钱包来放这些钱
like a... new purse to put all this money in.
亲爱的  我自己有钱买东西
Sweetie, I can buy my own stuff.
我现在有份好工作
I have a good job now.
我知道  我也以你为傲
I know, and I'm proud of you,
但我也可以为你做点事啊
but that doesn't mean I can't do something nice.
比如这样
Like this.
我不想为了这事跟你吵架
Okay, I don't want this to turn into a fight.
-我也不想  -很好
- I don't, either. - Great.
谢谢
Thank you.
-能把盐给我吗  谢谢  -好的
- Can you pass the salt, please? - Sure.
在我看来  这么做不仅用幽默打破了僵局
In my mind, that broke the tension with comedy
还会勾起性欲
and led to sex.
谢尔顿  你忙吗
Hey, Sheldon, you busy?
我一直都很忙
I'm always busy.
我的大脑能够处理复杂的多重任务
This mind is capable of advanced multitasking.
最近我一直在致力于证实
You know, currently, I'm attempting to solve
彭罗斯猜想
the Penrose conjecture,
我还在构思我证实彭罗斯猜想后
I'm composing my Nobel acceptance speech
被授予诺贝尔奖时的获奖感言
for when I've solved the Penrose conjecture,
我还在想美人鱼怎么生孩子
and I'm wondering how mermaids have babies.
她们不是把蛋产在石头上的吗
Don't they lay eggs on a rock?
现在我的大脑有空位想新事情了
Now I've got room for another thing.
你有什么事
What do you want?
我对矿井里的情况
So, I did a little research on what
做了一些调查
the conditions are like in the mines,
他们可能说得对
and the guys might be right--
井下情况艰苦啊
sounds pretty rough down there.
首先  井下很潮湿
For starters, it's very humid,
气温在37度左右
and about a hundred degrees.
我来自德克萨斯州  你来自印度
Well, I'm from Texas and you're from India--
我们对腋下汗味一点都不陌生  下一个
we're no strangers to the fragrant armpit. Next.
第二  那是个活矿井
It's also a live mine,
所以远处可能会发生爆炸声
so there'll be dynamite explosions going off in the distance.
我有一个患有乳糖不耐症
Yeah, I have a lactose-intolerant roommate
却还爱吃冰激凌的室友[放屁]  下一个
with a taste for ice cream. Next.
你每次得在底下待12个小时
Oh, you have to be down there for 12 hours at a time.
那又怎样  反正都得找地方待
Yeah? We have to be somewhere.
对了  那里没厕所
Well, there's no toilets--
我们都得排泄在一个桶里
we'll have to do our business in a bucket.
答案揭晓  我们不去了
So it's settled-- we're not doing it.
我明白  但是...
Look, I get it, but...
在拒绝这个难得的机会之前
before we pass up on an incredible opportunity,
我想到在霍华德上太空之前
I was thinking about when Howard was training to go to space,
曾在一个模拟环境里受训
they put him in a simulated environment.
有意思
Interesting.
你是建议我们
You're suggesting that we recreate
重现一下矿井的坏境
the conditions of the mine
-看看咱俩能否适应吗  -对
- to see if we can handle it. - Exactly.
-不错嘛  -我们该去哪里实验呢
- Very well. - So where should we do it?
我来搜"炙热[热辣]  黑暗[黑皮肤]  湿润"几个关键词
Well, I'll just Google "Hot, dark and moist,"
看看能搜出什么
see what comes up.
谢尔顿
Uh, Sheldon...
快看  搜出了好多视频呢
Oh, there, well, look, there's all kinds of videos.
你有空吗
Hey, you got a sec?
当然有
Hi. Sure.
我希望能再谈一下那些钱的事
I was hoping we could talk about the money again.
-亲爱的  算了吧  -不  不行
- Oh, sweetie, just forget about it. - No, no, no, no,
听我说  我知道昨晚事情发展得有点诡异
hear me out. I know things got a little weird last night.
上完床后在我床头柜上
Well, leaving an envelope full of cash
留下装满钱的信封
on my dresser after sex
的确算得上诡异
would count as weird.
我想出了一个很好的解决办法
Well, I think I came up with a pretty good solution.
我们何不把这钱存进一个共同账户里
Why don't we just put the money in a joint account?
这将是我俩第一笔共同资产
It'll be our first money together.
我们可以用它办婚礼  蜜月旅行  什么都可以
We can use it for the wedding, the honeymoon, whatever.
这主意太好了  我喜欢
You know what, that's great. I love that!
你当然会喜欢啦
Yeah, of course you do--
我可不止是床上小天才哦
I'm not just a genius in bed.
你当然是啦  宝贝
You sure are, baby.
你要和这笔钱独处一下吗
You two want to be alone?
我明白你不愿意留着这笔钱的原因
I want you to know I get why you don't want the money--
你找到了新工作  你很高兴
you've got this new job, you're excited
自己终于经济独立了
about being financially independent--
我也无比为你感到骄傲
and I am nothing but proud of you.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you so much.
听你这么说真是太开心了
It feels so good to hear you say that.
我也希望你知道
And I want you to know
我有了工作以后
that I get this job kind of changes
我俩之间的平衡发生了改变
the balance in our relationship,
我也在小心翼翼地处理这件事
and... I'm trying to be sensitive to that.
什么意思
What?
我只是觉得也许你纠结这笔钱
Well, I just think that maybe you're a little hung up
是因为我现在不再依赖你了
on the money because I'm less reliant on you now,
所以你感到害怕了
and that's a little scary.
可能吧
Maybe.
也有可能我是想对你好一点
Or maybe I tried to do something nice
结果可能你反而适应不了
and maybe you had a problem with it
因为你是个控制狂
because of your control issues.
控制狂
Control issues?
可能吧
Maybe.
也有...可能
Or... maybe...
现在我不再是失业的演员
now that I'm no longer an out-of-work actress
不会再付不起自己的饭钱
who can't pay for her own dinner,
让你有点没安全感了
that makes you a little insecure.
真不敢相信你会这么说
Well, I can't believe you'd say that.
你明知道我对于"没安全感"这事特别没安全感
You know how insecure I am about my insecurities.
好吧  对不起
You know what? I'm sorry.
为钱吵架这种事太愚蠢了
It's stupid to fight over money.
我也很抱歉
Yeah, I'm sorry, too.
我们还要一起共度余生呢
We're about to share the rest of our lives together.
这是我俩的钱  谁拿着又有什么关系
It's our money-- who cares who has it?
你说得对  有什么关系呢
Ugh! You're right-- who cares?
把钱从我裤子口袋拿出来
Get that money out of my back pocket
否则我拧断你手指
or I will break your fingers.
我从来不知道
All this time I never knew
这下面里有蒸汽通道
there were steam tunnels down here.
大部分大学都有这个
Most universities have them.
我读大学时  为求加入姐妹会
When I was an undergrad, I spent three days in one
曾在里面待了3天
pledging a sorority.
最后你加入了吗
Did you get in?
没  她们忘记了我在下面
No. They forgot I was there.
但我浑身的毛孔都被蒸开了
But it really opened up my pores.
根据我的调查
Well, according to my research,
这个入口下面的蒸汽通道
the steam tunnels below this access point
和矿井的环境最为相似
should be the closest analog to the mines.
这个会比健身房里的桑拿房
This is gonna be so much more accurate
更接近真实环境吧
than the steam room at the gym.
而且我们基本不可能看到
Plus, there's almost no chance
任何一位同事的半裸
we'll see any of our coworkers half naked.
或者是全裸
Or totally naked.
我爱霍华德
I love Howard,
可这混小子真是毫无节操啊
but the dude needs a little shame.
好了  艾米  这是你的对讲机
All right, Amy, this walkie-talkie is yours.
如果我们遇到问题  我就联系你
If we run into any problems, I'll contact you.
如果有情况发生  还记得规矩吗
And if anything bad happens, what's the rule?
先救你  有时间的话再回来救拉杰
Save you first; come back for Raj only if there's time.
我们不会有事的
We're going to be fine.
谢尔顿  我非常惊讶
Sheldon, I'm really impressed
你居然愿意来亲身体验
you're willing to try this.
不可否认  此举触及到了我所有广为人知的死穴
Well, admittedly, this brushes up against my well-known aversions
怕热  怕狭窄
to heat, small places,
怕往地下走
going below floor-level,
怕湿  怕舱口  怕梯子
dampness, hatches, ladders,
怕黑  怕回声
darkness, echoes,
还有怕在塑料桶里排泄
and eliminating in Home Depot buckets.
最后这项是新添的  但我感觉
That last one is quite new, but I have a feeling
它将压倒群雄  荣登名单宝座
that's gonna rocket to the top of the list.
我已经开始出汗了
I'm sweating already.
我就在你下面  所以我感觉到了
Yeah, as the person beneath you, allow me to say, I know.
这里有多热
How hot is it?
我看看  704度
Uh, let's see. 704?
不对  我看的是时间
No, wait, it's on "Clock."
真正的答案也好不到哪里去
No, the real answer isn't much better.
102华氏度[38.9摄氏度]
102 degrees.
这就是我们想要的
Well, that's what we wanted.
-和矿井差不多热  -没错
- This is as hot as the mines will be. - True.
谢尔顿矿井模拟日志  第一条
Sheldon's Mine Simulation Log, entry one.
库斯拉帕里老是重新叙述一些明摆的事情
Koothrappali's restating of the obvious
已经开始让我火大了
is already getting on my nerves.
谢谢邀请我们来你们家做客
Thanks again for having us.
别客气  你们俩想问什么事啊
Oh, of course. What did you guys want to talk about?
你们也知道我们已经订婚了
Well, you know, now that we're engaged,
所以想咨询你们一下
we had some questions about
夫妻之间如何处理金钱
how you handle money as a couple.
看吧  就说他们不是来邀我们玩换妻游戏
I told you they weren't gonna ask us to swing with them.
我本来就觉得不是啊
I didn't think they were going to.
我只是怕伤莱纳德自尊
I just wanted to have a way to say no
提前想好怎么拒绝而已
without hurting Leonard's feelings.
好吧  干得好
Well... nailed it.
你们想知道什么
So what did you want to know?
你们俩有曾经为钱吵过架吗
Well, do you guys ever fight over money?
当然有时候会啊
Sure, sometimes.
怎么说呢  多少会有一点别扭吧
I mean, it can be a little awkward
毕竟我现在挣钱比华仔多那么多
since I make so much more money than Howie.
你也没必要说"多那么多"吧
You didn't have to say "so much more."
是没必要  但是为了准确起见
Well, I didn't have to, but for the sake of accuracy
我觉得我应该这么说
I felt that I should.
我也为这段婚姻购置了很多重大资产好吗
I brought a lot of significant assets into the relationship, too.
比如说
Like what?
你那套不完整的《星际迷航》收藏挂盘吗
Your incomplete set of Star Trek collector plates?
忘了告诉你  我刚在易趣上买了最后一个
For your information, I just bought the last one
现在一套齐了
I needed on eBay.
不用跟老婆请示吗
Without asking me?
当时拍卖就剩三分钟了
There were only three minutes left in the auction
而且那个史考特挂盘是全新的
and it was a mint condition Scotty
而且卖家家里还不抽烟
from a smoke-free home.
多少钱  华仔
How much, Howie?
不多啦
Not a lot.
到底多少
How much?
我们别当着朋友的面说这个行吗
Let's not talk about this in front of our friends.
比去训鹰学校贵还是便宜
Was it more or less than falconry school?
我再说第十次  那是在团购网上团的
For the tenth time, that was a Groupon.
鬼才愿意跟他换妻咧
Like I would swing with him.
感觉如何
How you feeling?
还好
Good.
幽闭恐惧症有点发作
Little claustrophobic.
那赶快装设备
Let's set up the equipment.
这有助于转移你的注意力
It'll help take your mind off of it.
矿工经常会唱矿歌  让自己打起精神来
Miners often sang mining songs to keep their spirits up.
你会唱矿歌吗
Do you know any mining songs?
只记得热榜矿歌
Just the hits.
* 这里暗如地牢 *
* Where it's dark as a dungeon *
* 这里湿如露珠 *
* And it's damp as the dew *
歌词很美
That's pretty.
* 这里危险重重 *
* Where the dangers are double *
* 这里乐趣少少 *
* And the pleasures are few *
* 这里没有雨水 *
* Where the rain never falls *
* 这里缺乏阳光 *
* And the sun never shines *
* 没错  这里暗如地牢 *
* Yes, it's dark as a dungeon *
* 这里就是矿井 *
* Way down in the mine *
这歌词比我想象中要凄凉啊
It's a little more bleak than I thought.
* 死时祈祷 *
* Well, I pray when I dead *
* 时代变迁 *
* And the ages shall roll *
* 肉身变黑 *
* That my body will blacken *
* 化为煤炭 *
* And turn into coal *
歌词变阴森了
Getting kind of grim.
* 我在天国 *
* Then I'll look from the door *
* 望向地牢 *
* Of my heavenly home *
* 可怜矿工 *
* And pity the miner *
* 开采我骨 *
* That mines my poor bones. *
够了  不如唱两首小天后麦莉·赛勒斯的歌吧
Okay. How 'bout a little Miley Cyrus next?
美国年轻女明星  早期演出青春剧《汉娜·蒙塔纳》
现在则是走疯狂怪诞女歌手路线
他是哪位
Who's he?
说到乱花钱
Talk about wasted money.
怎么不说说我们信用卡之所以要交滞纳金
What about the late fees on our credit card
是因为有人总是不按时还款
because somebody didn't pay the bill on time?
或许我不用操心
Well, maybe I would have paid it
家里所有家务时  我会记得按时还款
if I wasn't also doing everything else around here.
你的意思是  我一点家务都不做吗
Oh, you're saying I don't do anything around here.
请看我的家务清单
Look at my chore chart.
-她居然给他列了家务清单  -看见了
- She made him a chore chart. - I see it.
"洗碗"  上面还有朵小红花呢
"Do the dishes." There's a star right there.
那是安慰小红花  往烤盘里倒点水
That was a pity star. Putting water in the roasting pan
然后扔到洗碗池里不叫"洗碗"
and leaving it in the sink is not doing the dishes.
你明知道那烤盘洗之前要泡一下
That pan had to soak and you know it.
等你领不到零用钱时
Well, don't come crying to me
可别哭着来求我
when you don't get your allowance.
那不是零用钱
It's not an allowance.
那是家用
It's a stipend!
我们说好不在我朋友面前
And we said we weren't gonna call it an allowance
提那叫零用钱的事
in front of my friends.
我以前不爱吃柠檬棒
I usually don't like lemon bars,
但你家的真的很好吃
but th-these are really good.
化身汉娜·蒙塔娜时
So, as Hannah Montana,
麦莉是一名风靡全球的流行偶像
Miley was a world-famous pop star.
但平时的她会脱下假发  像普通女孩那样
But then she would take off her wig and go to school
去上学
like a normal girl.
不用我说你也知道
Which, I don't have to tell you,
在那个年纪  光学校的事就很多烦恼了
at that age, is its own headache.
那也太荒谬了
That's preposterous.
怎么可能她一戴上假发  人们就认不出她了呢
How would she go unrecognized just by wearing a wig?
那你怎么不质疑  为什么超人戴上眼镜
But you're okay with Superman concealing his identity
就能隐藏自己身份呢
with a pair of glasses?
他不光只是戴上一副眼镜这么简单
He doesn't just put on a pair of glasses.
他前额那一小撮卷发没了
He combs back his curlicue
性格也变得温文尔雅
and affects a mild-mannered personality.
你们俩在下面还好吗
You guys doing okay down there?
都说要用对讲机啦
I told you to use the walkie-talkie!
你们俩在下面还好吗
You guys doing okay down there?
对讲机是用来应急  不是用来闲聊的
Please keep this channel clear for emergencies.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要去自动贩卖机那  你们需要什么吗
I'm going to the vending machine. Do you want anything?
这是模拟实验
This is a simulation.
我们必须靠我们带来的物品生存
We have to survive on the supplies we brought.
好吧  我就问问
Okay, just checking.
我们应该让她买点洋葱圈玉米片
We should have asked her to get some Funyuns.
当我们在真的矿坑里时
You're not going to have Funyuns
你哪来的洋葱圈玉米片吃啊
when we're a mile below the surface of the Earth.
如果是我们下矿坑时就带了的呢
What if we brought them down with us?
给我们买点洋葱圈玉米片
We'll take some Funyuns.
还要别的吗
Anything else?
还有约克薄荷饼
Some York Peppermint Patties,
两瓶胡椒博士汽水  还有...
a couple of Dr. Peppers, and...
跑去百思买商品看看有没有便携式DVD机
run to Best Buy and see if they have a portable DVD player
还有第一季的电视剧《汉娜·蒙塔娜》
and season one of a show called Hannah Montana.
让她买第二季
Have her get season two.
第一季的时候  剧情还在寻找风格
Season one, it was still finding itself.
抱歉让你们看到我们吵架
Sorry you guys had to see that.
-不必道歉  -是啊
- Oh, don't apologize. - Yeah.
这让我们更难假装这事从未发生过
It just makes it a lot harder to pretend it never happened.
因为我们收入有差距
Money's a sensitive subject for Howie
所以华仔对钱这个话题很敏感
because of the difference in our income.
这真的会困扰他吗
It really bothers him?
当然啊  男人都会有这种压力
Well, sure. There's still a lot of pressure
觉得自己必须撑起这头家
on guys to be providers.
所以虽然他很为我开心
So even though he's happy for me,
但其实他心里挺难受的
it's just a little tough on him.
-惨了  -怎么
- Uh-oh. - What?
如果我销售做得好
Well, if I do well in sales,
我很可能也会赚得比你多很多
I could end up making a lot more money than you.
不是问题  从小我就看我妈
Not a problem. I grew up with a mother
各种践踏我老爸的尊严
who emasculated my father financially
从金钱到各种方面  所以...
and in every other aspect of his life, so...
对我来说  这才是真爱的模样啊
...really, it's what I think love looks like.
我失陪一下  我去看看他怎么样了
I'll be right back. I'm gonna go check on him.
或许我们来这边也是好事
Maybe it's a good thing we came here.
-感觉就像是反面教材  -对啊
- It's like a lesson in what not to do. - Yeah.
我不想我们为金钱这样的蠢事而有了分歧
I don't want something dumb like money to come between us.
不会的  我们得保证把这些都谈好了
It won't. Let's just promise to figure this kind of stuff out
我们才结婚
before we get married.
你为什么这么管家婆啊
Why are you being so bossy?!
你为什么这么死小孩啊
Why are you being a baby?
我才不是死小孩  人家已经长大了
I'm not a baby! I'm a grown man,
我自己铺了床  我的小红花呢
and I made the bed. Now where's my star?
-我们是不是该走了  -且慢
- Should we go? - Hang on.
我想知道他有没拿到小红花
I want to see if he gets the star.
这是要热死人啊
Oh, this heat is brutal.
你来自热带国度印度
As someone from the tropical subcontinent of India,
应该知道  在潮湿环境下给自己扇风
you should know that fanning yourself in a humid environment
只会让体温升高
only raises your body temperature.
现在我懂为什么以前家里佣人给我扇风时
That does explain why the servants used to look so hot
看起来都这么热了
while they were fanning me.
我们别再去想现在有多难受
Let's get our minds off how uncomfortable we are.
我们继续看模拟仪表读数吧
We could take some more simulated instrument readings.
我现在只求
My major focus at the moment
幽闭恐惧症别占领我的心
is keeping my claustrophobia at bay.
-情况如何  -你觉得呢
- How's that going? - You tell me.
我现在感觉喘不过气
I feel like I can't breathe,
非常有冲动想把你撕成两半
and I am tempted to crack you open
再把你肺中的空气都吸光
and suck the air right out of your lungs.
谢尔顿  如果受不了  我们可以停止啊
Sheldon, if this is too much, we can stop.
不许停
We're not stopping.
那你也不用咬断我头吧
You don't have to bite my head off.
我道歉
I apologize.
我...
I j...
我被自己的内部斗争深深困扰
I'm plagued by an internal struggle.
如果你愿意在桶里释放出来
If you would just use the bucket,
你的"内部"会舒服很多
you'd be so much more comfortable.
我的"困扰"是情绪上的
My struggle is emotional.
是跟艾米有关吗
Is it Amy?
是暗物质
It's dark matter.
当我刚进入弦理论领域时  我是个奇才
When I entered the field of string theory, I was a prodigy.
上升到了受人敬仰的高度
I rose to a position of respect,
我也以为职业生涯
and I assumed my career would continue
会在这条路上一直向上
on that upward trajectory.
但现在我都30多岁了
Now here I am in my 30s,
却又要从头开始
I'm back at square one.
老实说  我有些害怕
And, frankly, it's frightening.
谢尔顿  你知道我害怕时都想什么吗
Sheldon, you know what I think of when I'm scared?
旅行者
Voyager.
旅行者号太空探测器
Voyager the space probe
还是《星际迷航:航海家号》电视剧
or Voyager the Star Trek TV show?
太空探测器
The space probe.
那就好  我现在又热又累
Good. Because I am too hot and tired
没力气告诉你我有多讨厌那部电视剧
to go on about how much I hate Voyager the TV show.
在我出生的那会
By the time I was born,
旅行者一号本来的任务应该就结束了
Voyager 1's mission was supposed to be over.
它已经探测完木星
It had seen Jupiter
土星以及它们所有的卫星
and Saturn and all their moons,
但它还是继续前进
but it kept going.
当我离开印度来美国时
When I left India for America,
那是我一生中最害怕的时刻
I was never more scared in my life.
前路茫茫  不知路在何方
I had no idea what lay ahead.
但每当我感到害怕时  我就会想
Whenever I feel that way, I think about how...
旅行者还在天上
Voyager is still out there
在太阳系外的某个地方
somewhere beyond our solar system,
继续朝着无人能想到它能到达的远方前进
going further than anyone ever thought it could.
别走啊  你能做到
Don't leave! You can do this!
谢尔顿  你还好吧
Sheldon, is everything okay?
库萨帕里来不及逃了
It's too late for Koothrappali.
咱们快跑吧
Let's go!
11分钟  比我预期的时间还久
11 minutes. That's longer than I thought.
它们在我衣服里
They're in my shirt!
它们在我衣服里  爬到我衣服里了
They're in my shirt! They're in my shirt!
好了  这绝对是我们可以拿这笔钱做的
Okay, this is definitely the most fun thing
最好玩的事情了
we can do with the money.
我从来没有在一堆钱上"做"过呢
I've never done it on a big old pile of cash before.
"我也是  莱纳德  这也是我的第一次"
"Me neither, Leonard. It's my first time, too."
抱歉我在钱的事情上让你不开心了
I'm so sorry I made you feel bad about the money stuff.
-没关系啦  -不  有关系
- It's okay. - No, it's not okay.
我想要我们俩平起平坐
I want us to be partners, equals.
像成熟恋情中的两个大人
Adults in a mature relationship.
我也想这样
I want that, too.
那现在来聊聊你的生日派对吧
Now, let's talk about your birthday party.
激光枪战  激光枪战
Ooh, laser tag, laser tag. Oh!
你真的想要我转录下来吗
Do you really need me to transcribe this?
你不是在为我做
You're not doing it for me.
你是在为未来的人类造福
You're doing it for future generations
让他们从我的困境中学习
who will benefit from my struggle.
谢尔顿矿井模拟日志
Sheldon's Mine Simulation Log,
第四条
entry four:
我的巧克力条融化了
my Kit Kat has melted.
满盘皆输
All is lost.
你敢说你是朋友吗
You call yourself a friend?!
我在想着帮助你
I was trying to help you!
结果一有问题
And at the first sign of trouble
你丫撒腿就跑  留我被万鼠啮咬
you ran away, leaving me to fend off a family of rats!
你个不折不扣的自私鬼
You're a completely selfish human being
你从里到外都是个孬种
and a... and a physical and a moral coward!
他总是说一些明摆的事情  好烦人
His statements of the obvious continue to annoy.